<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<!DOCTYPE book PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.4//EN" "../../../docbook-xml/docbookx.dtd"[]>
<!--
  Licensed to the Apache Software Foundation (ASF) under one
  or more contributor license agreements.  See the NOTICE file
  distributed with this work for additional information
  regarding copyright ownership.  The ASF licenses this file
  to you under the Apache License, Version 2.0 (the
  "License"); you may not use this file except in compliance
  with the License.  You may obtain a copy of the License at

    http://www.apache.org/licenses/LICENSE-2.0

  Unless required by applicable law or agreed to in writing,
  software distributed under the License is distributed on an
  "AS IS" BASIS, WITHOUT WARRANTIES OR CONDITIONS OF ANY
  KIND, either express or implied.  See the License for the
  specific language governing permissions and limitations
  under the License.
-->
<book>
	<bookinfo>
		<title>Apache Directory Studio</title>
		<subtitle>User's Guide</subtitle>
		<releaseinfo>Version 1.0.0</releaseinfo>
		<copyright>
			<year>2007</year>
			<holder>Apache Software Foundation</holder>
		</copyright>
		<legalnotice>
			<literallayout class="monospaced">
				Licensed to the Apache Software Foundation (ASF) under one
				or more contributor license agreements.  See the NOTICE file
				distributed with this work for additional information
				regarding copyright ownership.  The ASF licenses this file
				to you under the Apache License, Version 2.0 (the
				"License"); you may not use this file except in compliance
				with the License.  You may obtain a copy of the License at
				
				  <ulink url="http://www.apache.org/licenses/LICENSE-2.0">http://www.apache.org/licenses/LICENSE-2.0</ulink>
				
				Unless required by applicable law or agreed to in writing,
				software distributed under the License is distributed on an
				"AS IS" BASIS, WITHOUT WARRANTIES OR CONDITIONS OF ANY
				KIND, either express or implied.  See the License for the
				specific language governing permissions and limitations
				under the License.
			</literallayout>		
		</legalnotice>
	</bookinfo>
	
	<!-- GETTING STARTED CHAPTER -->
	<chapter id="gettingstarted">
		<title>Getting started</title>
		
		<!-- DOWNLOAD AND INSTALLATION SECTION -->
		<section id="download_install">
			<title>Download and install</title>
			<para>The latest version of Apache Directory Studio can be downloaded from the 
			Apache Directory Studio Downloads page, at this address : 
			<ulink url="http://directory.apache.org/studio/downloads.html">http://directory.apache.org/studio/downloads.html</ulink>.</para>
			<para><emphasis role="strong">System requirements</emphasis></para>
			<para>
				<itemizedlist>
					<listitem>Mac OS X 10.4 or later, Windows, Linux</listitem>
					<listitem><ulink url="http://www.java.com/">Java Runtime Environment</ulink> 5 or later</listitem>
				</itemizedlist>
			</para>
			<para><emphasis role="strong">Installing on Mac OS X</emphasis></para>
			<para>Follow this installation process:</para>
			<para>
				<itemizedlist>
					<listitem>Step 1: Double-click the downloaded package to mount the Apache Directory Studio DMG.</listitem>
					<listitem>Step 2: Drag and drop the Apache Directory Studio application to your Applications folder.</listitem>
				</itemizedlist>
			</para>
			<para><emphasis role="strong">Installing on Linux</emphasis></para>
			<para>Follow this installation process:</para>
			<para>
				<itemizedlist>
					<listitem>Step 1: Uncompress the Tar Gzip archive ('tar xzf ApacheDirectoryStudio-1.0.0-linux-i386.tar.gz' for the i386 Linux version).</listitem>
					<listitem>Step 2: Move the ApacheDirectoryStudio folder to the location of your choice.</listitem>
				</itemizedlist>
			</para>
			<para><emphasis role="strong">Installing on Windows</emphasis></para>
			<para>Follow this installation process:</para>
			<para>
				<itemizedlist>
					<listitem>Unzip the Zip archive.</listitem>
					<listitem>Run the installer and follow install instructions.</listitem>
				</itemizedlist>
			</para>
		</section>
	</chapter>
	
	<!-- TASKS CHAPTER -->
	<chapter id="tasks">
		<title>Tasks</title>
		
		<!-- RUNNING LDAP STUDIO SECTION -->
		<section id="running">
			<title>Running Apache Directory Studio</title>
			<para><emphasis role="strong">Mac OS X</emphasis></para>
			<para>If you followed the instructions on the "Download and install" page, simply double-click the Apache Directory Studio application located in your Applications folder.</para>
			<para><emphasis role="strong">Linux</emphasis></para>
			<para>After installing the Apache Directory Studio in a directory, you can start Apache Directory Studio by running the ApacheDirectoryStudio executable included with the release.</para>
			<para><emphasis role="strong">Windows</emphasis></para>
			<para>If you followed the instructions on the "Download and install" page, simply click on the Apache Directory Studio executable in the Apache Directory Studio folder located in the All programs item of the Start menu.</para>
		</section>
		
		<!-- UPDATING LDAP STUDIO SECTION -->
		<section id="updating">
			<title>Updating Apache Directory Studio</title>
			<para>To check to see whether there are updates for features of Apache Directory Studio (requires Internet access):</para>
			<para>1. Click  <emphasis role="strong">Help > Software Updates > <imageobject><imagedata contentdepth="1em" fileref="images/search-updates.png" format="PNG" /></imageobject> Search for updates...</emphasis>. 
				This will contact Apache Directory Studio Web site to discover what versions of those features are available. The potential 
				upgrades are presented in on the next page.</para>
			<para>2. Select the feature versions that you wish to upgrade, and click <emphasis role="strong">Next</emphasis>.</para>
			<para>3. Carefully review the license agreements for the upgraded features. If the terms of 
				all these licenses are acceptable, check "I accept the terms in the license agreements." Do not proceed to 
				download the features if the license terms are not acceptable.</para>
			<para>4. Feature versions can be digitally signed by the company that provides them. This allows you to 
				verify more easily that the features and plug-ins that are about to be downloaded and installed are coming from 
				a trusted supplier.</para>
			<para>Click <emphasis role="strong">Install</emphasis> to allow the downloading and installing to proceed.</para>
			<para>5. Once all the features and plug-ins have been downloaded successfully and their files installed into the product on the 
			local computer, a new configuration that incorporates these features and plug-ins will be formulated. Click <emphasis role="strong">Yes</emphasis> when asked to exit 
			and restart the Workbench for the changes to take effect.</para>
			
			<!-- INSPECTING THE CURRENT CONFIGURATION SECTION -->
			<section id="inspecting_configuration">
				<title>Inspecting the current configuration</title>
				<para>The <emphasis role="strong">Help > <imageobject><imagedata contentdepth="1em" fileref="images/about.png" format="PNG" /></imageobject> About Apache Directory Studio</emphasis> dialog shows most of the important information about the features and plug-in configured
					 in the product. To find out further detailed information about the current configuration:</para>
				<para>1. Open the update configuration manager by clicking <emphasis role="strong"> Help > Software Updates > <imageobject><imagedata contentdepth="1em" fileref="images/manage-configuration.png" format="PNG" /></imageobject> Manage Configuration</emphasis>. 
					This opens the Product Configuration dialog.</para>
				<para>2. In the Product Configuration dialog expand the root node (current  configuration). The first tier of items are locations on 
					the local computer where the files for features and plug-ins are stored. For a typical product, all features are installed in a single 
					directory sub-tree. However, a feature that is installed as an extension of another product are usually located in a separate directory 
					sub-tree.</para>
				<para>3. Expand the location to see the feature versions installed there.</para>
				<para>4. The nesting of the features indicates which child features are included in a given parent feature. Nested features act as a unit.
				</para>
				<para>5. Select a feature version and click <emphasis role="strong">Show Properties</emphasis> to open the Properties dialog which presents more detailed information about 
					the selected feature.</para>
				<para>6. Click <emphasis role="strong">Show Disabled Features</emphasis> filter on the toolbar of the Product Configuration dialog. Any feature versions that are disabled are 
					now shown (you might not have any). Disabled feature versions are ones that are installed on the local computer but excluded from the 
					current configuration. At most one version of any given feature can be present in a given configuration; usually the ones with the lower 
					version numbers will be in a disabled state.</para>
				<para>7. In the Properties dialog of a feature, click <emphasis role="strong">Status</emphasis> to find out whether the selected feature is configured exactly as packaged. The 
					status will show when a feature's plug-ins are present at different versions, or disabled due to missing prerequisite plug-ins that are 
					expected to be supplied by some other feature.</para>
			</section>
			
			<!-- ENABLING, DISABLING AND UNINSTALLING FEATURES SECTION -->
			<section id="enabling_disabling_uninstalling_features">
				<title>Enabling, disabling and uninstalling features</title>
				<para>You can browse and manage your configuration from the <emphasis role="strong">Product Configuration dialog</emphasis>. Open the <emphasis role="strong">Product Configuration</emphasis> dialog by 
					clicking <emphasis role="strong"> Help > Software Updates > <imageobject><imagedata contentdepth="1em" fileref="images/manage-configuration.png" format="PNG" /></imageobject> Manage Configuration</emphasis>.</para>
				<para>1. <emphasis role="strong">Disabling a feature</emphasis>: select the feature and click <emphasis role="strong">Disable</emphasis> in the right pane of the dialog. This option is available only when the 
					feature is currently enabled, and the feature is either an optional feature or a root feature (not included by other features).</para>
				<para>2. <emphasis role="strong">Enabling a feature</emphasis>: First, ensure <emphasis role="strong">Show Disabled Features</emphasis>  is turned on in the tool bar. Then, select a disabled optional or root 
					feature and click <emphasis role="strong">Enable</emphasis> in the right pane of the dialog.</para>
				<para>3. <emphasis role="strong">Uninstalling a feature</emphasis>: features that you have installed using the update manager can be uninstalled, provided they are already 
					disabled, or that they are optional or root features. If the feature is disabled, make sure <emphasis role="strong">Show Disabled Features</emphasis> is turned on in the tool bar. 
					Select the feature and click <emphasis role="strong">Uninstall</emphasis> in the right page of the dialog.</para>
			</section>
			
		</section>
		
		<!-- REPORTING A BUG SECTION -->
		<section id="reporting_a_bug">
			<title>Reporting a bug</title>
			<para>Use the <emphasis role="strong">Help > <imageobject><imagedata contentdepth="1em" fileref="images/bug-report.png" format="PNG" /></imageobject> Report a bug...</emphasis> menu item to report any bug you find on Apache Directory Studio.</para>
			<para>You will be redirected on your default Web browser to our issue tracking software called Jira.</para>
			<para>You can also reach it using this address : <ulink url="https://issues.apache.org/jira/browse/DIRSTUDIO">https://issues.apache.org/jira/browse/DIRSTUDIO</ulink></para>
			<para><imageobject><imagedata scale="50" fileref="images/jira-screenshot.png" format="PNG" /></imageobject></para>
			<para>To report a bug:</para>
			<para>1. Click the <emphasis role="strong">Create a new issue</emphasis> link in the menu.</para>
			<para>2. Make sure the selected project is 'Directory Apache Directory Studio' and the issue type is 'Bug'. Click <emphasis role="strong">Next</emphasis>.</para>
			<para>3. Fill in the issue form giving the more details you can on the bug you have found.</para>
			<para>4. Click the <emphasis role="strong">Create</emphasis> button to create the new issue.</para>
		</section>
		
	</chapter>
	
	<!-- REFERENCE -->
	<chapter id="reference">
		<title>Reference</title>
		
		<!-- PREFERENCES SECTION -->
		<section id="preferences">
			<title>Preferences</title>
			<para>The <emphasis role="strong">Preferences</emphasis> dialog is the dialog used to set user preferences. The Preferences dialog pages can be searched using the filter function. To filter by matching the page title, simply type the name of the page you are seeking and the available pages will be presented below. The filter also searches on keywords such as appearance and java. The history controls allow you to navigate through previously viewed pages. To step back or forward several pages at a time, click the drop down arrow and a list of the most recently viewed preference pages will appear.</para>
			<para>The Preferences dialog can be found from the main workbench <emphasis role="strong">Window</emphasis> menu under <emphasis role="strong">Window > <imageobject><imagedata contentdepth="1em" fileref="images/preferences.png" format="PNG" /></imageobject> Preferences</emphasis>. Preference pages contributed by plug-ins will be found in this dialog.</para>
			
			<!-- HELP SECTION -->
			<section id="help">
				<title>Help</title>
				<para>On the <emphasis role="strong">Help</emphasis> preferences page, you can indicate how to display help information.</para>
				<para>
					<informaltable>
						<tgroup cols="3">
							<colspec colname="Option" colwidth="1* "/>
							<colspec colname="Description" colwidth="2*" />
							<colspec colname="Default" colwidth="1*" />
							<thead>
								<row>
									<entry>Option</entry>
									<entry>Description</entry>
									<entry>Default</entry>
								</row>
							</thead>
							<tbody>
								<row>
									<entry>Use external browsers</entry>
									<entry>If embedded web browser is supported on your system, help window uses an embedded help browser to display help contents, whenever possible, and this option is available. Select it, to force help to use external browsers. Use "Web Browser" preference page to select browser to use.</entry>
									<entry>Off</entry>
								</row>
								<row>
									<entry>Open window context help</entry>
									<entry>This option allows you to determine whether the window context help will be opened in a dynamic help view or in an infopop.</entry>
									<entry>in a dynamic help view</entry>
								</row>
								<row>
									<entry>Open dialog context help</entry>
									<entry>This option allows you to determine whether the dialog context help will be opened in a dynamic help section of help view or in an infopop.</entry>
									<entry>in dialog tray</entry>
								</row>
								<row>
									<entry>Help view document open mode</entry>
									<entry>This option allows you to determine whether the documents selected in the help view will be opened in place or in the editor area.</entry>
									<entry>Open in place</entry>
								</row>
								<row>
									<entry>Search</entry>
									<entry>Determines whether potential hits should be shown while searching. Showing potential hits will increase search performance, at the cost of potential loss of accuracy.</entry>
									<entry>Show all potential hits (faster)</entry>
								</row>
							</tbody>
						</tgroup>
					</informaltable>
				</para>
				<para>Here is what the Help preferences page looks like:</para>
				<para>
					<screenshot>
						<mediaobject>
							<imageobject>
								<imagedata scale="50"
									fileref="images/help_screen.png" format="PNG" />
							</imageobject>
						</mediaobject>
					</screenshot>
				</para>
				
				
				<!-- HELP SERVER SECTION -->
				<section id="help_server">
					<title>Help Server</title>
					<para>Help system includes an internal server that serves help contents to the browser. Use the <emphasis role="strong">Help > Help Server</emphasis> preference page to change the interface and port that the servers uses. You should only change these settings if you experience problems and cannot view help with the default preferences.</para>
					<para>
						<informaltable>
							<tgroup cols="3">
								<colspec colname="Option" colwidth="1* "/>
								<colspec colname="Description" colwidth="2*" />
								<colspec colname="Default" colwidth="1*" />
								<thead>
									<row>
										<entry>Option</entry>
										<entry>Description</entry>
										<entry>Default</entry>
									</row>
								</thead>
								<tbody>
									<row>
										<entry>Host</entry>
										<entry>Name or address of a local IP interface to be used by the server.</entry>
										<entry>blank</entry>
									</row>
									<row>
										<entry>Port</entry>
										<entry>IP port for server to listen on. If no port is specified for the value, a port will be assigned by the operating system.</entry>
										<entry>blank</entry>
									</row>
								</tbody>
							</tgroup>
						</informaltable>
					</para>
					<para>Here is what the Help preferences page looks like:</para>
					<para>
						<screenshot>
							<mediaobject>
								<imageobject>
									<imagedata scale="50"
										fileref="images/help-server_screen.png" format="PNG" />
								</imageobject>
							</mediaobject>
						</screenshot>
					</para>
				</section>
				
			</section> <!-- end Help Section -->
			
			<section id="install_update">
				<title>Install/Update</title>
				<para>The following preferences can be changed on the Install/Update page:</para>
				<para>
						<informaltable>
							<tgroup cols="3">
								<colspec colname="Option" colwidth="1* "/>
								<colspec colname="Description" colwidth="2*" />
								<colspec colname="Default" colwidth="1*" />
								<thead>
									<row>
										<entry>Option</entry>
										<entry>Description</entry>
										<entry>Default</entry>
									</row>
								</thead>
								<tbody>
									<row>
										<entry>Maximum number of 'History' configurations</entry>
										<entry>Maximum number of configurations you want maintained in the configuration history. These configurations are maintained to allow you to revert to a previous configuration of installed feature versions.</entry>
										<entry>100</entry>
									</row>
									<row>
										<entry>Check digital signatures of downloaded archives</entry>
										<entry>This option will check for digital signatures of downloaded archives.</entry>
										<entry>On</entry>
									</row>
									<row>
										<entry>Valid updates</entry>
										<entry>
										 	Assuming that feature versions use the form 'major.minor.service', you can select what update level you want to choose from:
											<itemizedlist>
												<listitem>equivalent : Only service updates will be displayed.</listitem>
												<listitem>compatible : Service updates and minor updates will be displayed.</listitem>
											</itemizedlist>
										</entry>
										<entry>equivalent</entry>
									</row>
									<row>
										<entry>Update Policy</entry>
										<entry>The update policy URL that controls the redirection of update sites within an organization.</entry>
										<entry>No policy</entry>
									</row>
									<row>
										<entry>Proxy settings</entry>
										<entry>Allows connection to the remote server from behind the firewall. When enabled, proxy host address (required) and port number (optional) can be specified.</entry>
										<entry>No proxy</entry>
									</row>
								</tbody>
							</tgroup>
						</informaltable>
					</para>
					<para>Here is what the Install/Update preferences page looks like:</para>
					<para>
						<screenshot>
							<mediaobject>
								<imageobject>
									<imagedata scale="50"
										fileref="images/install-update_screen.png" format="PNG" />
								</imageobject>
							</mediaobject>
						</screenshot>
					</para>
			</section>
			
			<!-- TEXT EDITORS SECTION -->
			<section id="text_editors">
				<title>Text Editors</title>
				<para>The following preferences can be changed on the <emphasis role="strong">Text Editors</emphasis> page.</para>
				<para>
					<informaltable>
						<tgroup cols="3">
							<colspec colname="Option" colwidth="1* "/>
							<colspec colname="Description" colwidth="2*" />
							<colspec colname="Default" colwidth="1*" />
							<thead>
								<row>
									<entry>Option</entry>
									<entry>Description</entry>
									<entry>Default</entry>
								</row>
							</thead>
							<tbody>
								<row>
									<entry>Displayed tab width</entry>
									<entry>This option allows you to set the displayed tab width for the text editor.</entry>
									<entry>4</entry>
								</row>
								<row>
									<entry>Undo history size</entry>
									<entry>This option allows you to undo the history size for the text editor.</entry>
									<entry>25</entry>
								</row>
								<row>
									<entry>Highlight current line</entry>
									<entry>This option controls whether or the current line is highlighted or not.</entry>
									<entry>On</entry>
								</row>
								<row>
									<entry>Show print margin</entry>
									<entry>This option controls whether the print margin is visible or not.</entry>
									<entry>Off</entry>
								</row>
								<row>
									<entry>Show line numbers</entry>
									<entry>This option controls whether or not line numbers are shown on the left side of the text editor.</entry>
									<entry>Off</entry>
								</row>
								<row>
									<entry>Show range indicators</entry>
									<entry>This option controls whether or not range indicators are shown in the text editor.</entry>
									<entry>On</entry>
								</row>
								<row>
									<entry>Support hyperlink style navigation</entry>
									<entry>This option controls whether or not hyperlink style navigation is supported.</entry>
									<entry>On</entry>
								</row>
								<row>
									<entry>Hyperlink style navigation key modifier</entry>
									<entry>This option sets the hyperlink style navigation key modifier.</entry>
									<entry>Ctrl</entry>
								</row>
								<row>
									<entry>Disable overwrite typing mode</entry>
									<entry>This option controls whether the overwrite typing mode is enabled or disabled.</entry>
									<entry>Off</entry>
								</row>
								<row>
									<entry>Appearance color options</entry>
									<entry>This option controls various appearance colors.</entry>
									<entry>-</entry>
								</row>
							</tbody>
						</tgroup>
					</informaltable>
				</para>
				<para>Here is what the Help preferences page looks like:</para>
				<para>
					<screenshot>
						<mediaobject>
							<imageobject>
								<imagedata scale="50"
									fileref="images/text-editors_screen.png" format="PNG" />
							</imageobject>
						</mediaobject>
					</screenshot>
				</para>
				
				<!-- ACCESSIBILITY SECTION -->
				<section id="accessibility">
					<title>Accessibility</title>
					<para>The following preferences can be changed on the <emphasis role="strong">Text Editors > Accessibility</emphasis> page.</para>
					<para>
						<informaltable>
							<tgroup cols="3">
								<colspec colname="Option" colwidth="1* "/>
								<colspec colname="Description" colwidth="2*" />
								<colspec colname="Default" colwidth="1*" />
								<thead>
									<row>
										<entry>Option</entry>
										<entry>Description</entry>
										<entry>Default</entry>
									</row>
								</thead>
								<tbody>
									<row>
										<entry>Use custom caret </entry>
										<entry>This option replaces the original caret with a custom caret and shows a different caret for Overwrite and Insert mode.</entry>
										<entry>On</entry>
									</row>
									<row>
										<entry>Enable thick caret</entry>
										<entry> This option replaces the original caret with a more visible, thicker caret.</entry>
										<entry>On</entry>
									</row>
									<row>
										<entry>Use characters to show changes on line number bar</entry>
										<entry>Quick Diff shows the changes in a vertical ruler using colors. Color blind persons can enable this option to show the differences with different characters in the line number ruler.</entry>
										<entry>Off</entry>
									</row>
								</tbody>
							</tgroup>
						</informaltable>
					</para>
					<para>Here is what the Accesibility preferences page looks like:</para>
					<para>
						<screenshot>
							<mediaobject>
								<imageobject>
									<imagedata scale="50"
										fileref="images/accessibility_screen.png" format="PNG" />
								</imageobject>
							</mediaobject>
						</screenshot>
					</para>
				</section>
				
				<!-- ANNOTATIONS SECTION -->
				<section id="annotations">
					<title>Annotations</title>
					<para>The following preferences can be changed on the <emphasis role="strong">Text Editors > Annotations</emphasis> preference page.</para>
					<para>
						<informaltable>
							<tgroup cols="2">
								<colspec colname="Option" colwidth="1* "/>
								<colspec colname="Description" colwidth="2*" />
								<colspec colname="Default" colwidth="1*" />
								<thead>
									<row>
										<entry>Option</entry>
										<entry>Description</entry>
									</row>
								</thead>
								<tbody>
									<row>
										<entry>Show in Text as</entry>
										<entry>This option controls whether the selected annotation type is shown in the text. The corresponding text will be underlined with squiggles or highlighted.</entry>
									</row>
									<row>
										<entry>Show in Overview ruler</entry>
										<entry>This option controls whether the overview ruler on the right side of the text editor is shown.</entry>
									</row>
									<row>
										<entry>Show in Vertical ruler  </entry>
										<entry>This option controls whether the selected annotation type is shown in the vertical ruler.</entry>
									</row>
									<row>
										<entry>Color</entry>
										<entry>This option controls the color for the selected annotation type.</entry>
									</row>
								</tbody>
							</tgroup>
						</informaltable>
					</para>
					<para>Here is what the Annotations preferences page looks like:</para>
					<para>
						<screenshot>
							<mediaobject>
								<imageobject>
									<imagedata scale="50"
										fileref="images/annotations_screen.png" format="PNG" />
								</imageobject>
							</mediaobject>
						</screenshot>
					</para>
				</section>
				
				<!-- LINKED MODE SECTION -->
				<section id="linked_mode">
					<title>Linked Mode</title>
					<para>Here is what the Linked Mode preferences page looks like:</para>
					<para>
						<screenshot>
							<mediaobject>
								<imageobject>
									<imagedata scale="50"
										fileref="images/linked-mode_screen.png" format="PNG" />
								</imageobject>
							</mediaobject>
						</screenshot>
					</para>
				</section>
				
				<!-- QUICK DIFF SECTION -->
				<section id="quick_diff">
					<title>Quick Diff</title>
					<para>The following preferences can be changed on the <emphasis role="strong">Text Editors > Quick Diff</emphasis> preference page.</para>
					<para>
						<informaltable>
							<tgroup cols="3">
								<colspec colname="Option" colwidth="1* "/>
								<colspec colname="Description" colwidth="2*" />
								<colspec colname="Default" colwidth="1*" />
								<thead>
									<row>
										<entry>Option</entry>
										<entry>Description</entry>
										<entry>Default</entry>
									</row>
								</thead>
								<tbody>
									<row>
										<entry>Enable quick diff</entry>
										<entry>This option will enable or disable the quick diff option.</entry>
										<entry>On</entry>
									</row>
									<row>
										<entry>Show differences in overview ruler</entry>
										<entry>This option will show differences in the overview ruler.</entry>
										<entry>Off</entry>
									</row>
									<row>
										<entry>Colors - Changes</entry>
										<entry>This option controls the color of changes.</entry>
										<entry>-</entry>
									</row>
									<row>
										<entry>Colors - Additions</entry>
										<entry>This option controls the color of additions. </entry>
										<entry>-</entry>
									</row>
									<row>
										<entry>Colors - Deletions</entry>
										<entry>This option controls the color of deletions. </entry>
										<entry>-</entry>
									</row>
									<row>
										<entry>Use this reference source</entry>
										<entry>
											This option sets which reference to use as the base for generating quick diff comparisons. Options are:
											<itemizedlist>
				    							<listitem>Version on Disk: Current file is compared against the last saved version on disk.</listitem>
												<listitem>Latest CVS Revision: Current file is compared against the latest CVS revision for the file.</listitem>
			    							</itemizedlist>
										</entry>
										<entry>Version on Disk</entry>
									</row>
								</tbody>
							</tgroup>
						</informaltable>
					</para>
					<para>Here is what the Quick Diff preferences page looks like:</para>
					<para>
						<screenshot>
							<mediaobject>
								<imageobject>
									<imagedata scale="50"
										fileref="images/quick-diff_screen.png" format="PNG" />
								</imageobject>
							</mediaobject>
						</screenshot>
					</para>
				</section>
				
				<!-- SPELLING SECTION -->
				<section id="spelling">
					<title>Spelling</title>
					<para>The following preferences can be changed on the <emphasis role="strong">Text Editors > Spelling</emphasis> preference page.</para>
					<para>
						<informaltable>
							<tgroup cols="3">
								<colspec colname="Option" colwidth="1* "/>
								<colspec colname="Description" colwidth="2*" />
								<colspec colname="Default" colwidth="1*" />
								<thead>
									<row>
										<entry>Option</entry>
										<entry>Description</entry>
										<entry>Default</entry>
									</row>
								</thead>
								<tbody>
									<row>
										<entry>Enable spell checking</entry>
										<entry>This option enables spell checking.</entry>
										<entry>Off</entry>
									</row>
									<row>
										<entry>Ignore words with digits </entry>
										<entry>This option ignores words with digits when performing spell checking.</entry>
										<entry>Off</entry>
									</row>
									<row>
										<entry>Ignore mixed case words </entry>
										<entry>This option ignores mixed case words when performing spell checking.</entry>
										<entry>Off</entry>
									</row>
									<row>
										<entry>Ignore sentence capitalization</entry>
										<entry>This option ignores sentence capitalization when performing spell checking. </entry>
										<entry>Off</entry>
									</row>
									<row>
										<entry>Ignore upper case words</entry>
										<entry>This option ignores upper case words when performing spell checking.</entry>
										<entry>Off</entry>
									</row>
									<row>
										<entry>Ignore internet addresses</entry>
										<entry>This option ignores internet addresses when performing spell checking.</entry>
										<entry>Off</entry>
									</row>
									<row>
										<entry>Platform dictionary</entry>
										<entry>This option selects a platform dictionary to use.</entry>
										<entry>-</entry>
									</row>
									<row>
										<entry>User defined dictionary</entry>
										<entry>This option selects a User defined dictionary to use.</entry>
										<entry>-</entry>
									</row>
									<row>
										<entry>Maximum number of correction proposals</entry>
										<entry>This option limits the possible corrections displayed to the given value.</entry>
										<entry>20</entry>
									</row>
									<row>
										<entry>Make dictionary available to content assist</entry>
										<entry>This option allows content assist to use the dictionary when constructing its choices.</entry>
										<entry>20</entry>
									</row>
								</tbody>
							</tgroup>
						</informaltable>
					</para>
					<para>Here is what the Spelling preferences page looks like:</para>
					<para>
						<screenshot>
							<mediaobject>
								<imageobject>
									<imagedata width="15cm"
										fileref="images/spelling_screen.png" format="PNG" />
								</imageobject>
							</mediaobject>
						</screenshot>
					</para>
				</section>
				
			</section> <!-- end Text Editors Section -->
			
		</section> <!-- end Preferences Section -->
		
		<!-- RELEASE NOTES SECTION -->
		<section id="release_notes">
			<title>Release notes</title>
            <para><emphasis role="strong">Apache Directory Studio 1.0.0</emphasis> (2007, september 3rd) : initial release</para>
            <para>Includes :</para>
            <para>
                <itemizedlist spacing="normal" mark="bullet">
					<listitem>Apache Directory Studio Apache DS Configuration 1.0.0</listitem>
					<listitem>Apache Directory Studio LDAP Browser 1.0.0</listitem>
					<listitem>Apache Directory Studio LDIF Editor 1.0.0</listitem>
					<listitem>Apache Directory Studio RCP 1.0.0</listitem>
					<listitem>Apache Directory Studio Schema Editor 1.0.0</listitem>
                </itemizedlist>
            </para>
        </section> <!-- end Release Notes Section -->
        
	</chapter>
</book>
