<!--
  Licensed to the Apache Software Foundation (ASF) under one
  or more contributor license agreements.  See the NOTICE file
  distributed with this work for additional information
  regarding copyright ownership.  The ASF licenses this file
  to you under the Apache License, Version 2.0 (the
  "License"); you may not use this file except in compliance
  with the License.  You may obtain a copy of the License at

    http://www.apache.org/licenses/LICENSE-2.0

  Unless required by applicable law or agreed to in writing,
  software distributed under the License is distributed on an
  "AS IS" BASIS, WITHOUT WARRANTIES OR CONDITIONS OF ANY
  KIND, either express or implied.  See the License for the
  specific language governing permissions and limitations
  under the License.
-->
<section id="tools_ldap_perspective">
	<title>LDAP perspective</title>
	<para>
		The LDAP Studio Browser plug-in provides a LDAP perspective. It is designed for working
		with an LDAP directory (browse, edit, search) as well as for editing LDIF
		files. The views and edtiors are arranged as follows:
	</para>
	<para>
		<screenshot>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata
						fileref="images/tools_ldap_perspective_1.png" format="PNG" />
				</imageobject>
			</mediaobject>
		</screenshot>
	</para>
	<para>
		The bottom left view shows all the <emphasis role="strong">Connections</emphasis>. 
		It is used to create, edit, delete, open and close connections. 
		When selecting a single connection the LDAP Browser shows the content of the 
		selected connection.
	</para>		
	<para>
		The <emphasis role="strong">LDAP Browser view</emphasis> is on the top left. 
		It shows the directory information tree (DIT), the persistent searches
		and bookmarks of the selected connection.
		With the LDAP Browser you are able to navigate and modify the DIT, 
		perform searches and manage bookmarks.
		When selecting a single entry the Entry editor shows its attributes 
		and values. When selecting a single search the Search Result editor 
		shows the search results.
	</para>
	<para>
		The editor area in the top middle. The following LDAP specific editors
		are available:
		<itemizedlist>
			<listitem>
				<para>The <emphasis role="strong">Entry editor</emphasis> 
				displays the attributes and values of the currently selected entry. 
				Further it is possilbe to add, edit and delete	attributes</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>The <emphasis role="strong">Search Result editor</emphasis>
				shows the result of the currently selected search in a table. 
				Further it is possible to edit the search result in a 
				spreadsheet-like manner.</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>					
				<para>With the <emphasis role="strong">Schema Browser</emphasis> 
				you could browse the schema with its object class and attribute 
				definitions.</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>The <emphasis role="strong">LDIF editor</emphasis> is a 
				rich editor to create LDIF files. It provides well-known Eclipse 
				features like syntax highlighting and content assistance</para>
			</listitem>
		</itemizedlist>
	</para>
	<para>
		The <emphasis role="strong">Outline view</emphasis> on the top right 
		displays the structure of the entry currently opended in the entry editor or 
		the structured outline of the currently opened LDIF file.
	</para>
	<para>
		The bottom centered view displays all <emphasis role="strong">Modifications</emphasis>
		made on the currently selected connections as LIDF change records.
	</para>
	<para>
		The bottom right <emphasis role="strong">Progress view</emphasis> displays 
		long-running operations like connecting to the directory or 
		import/export operations.
	</para>
</section>