<!--
	Licensed to the Apache Software Foundation (ASF) under one
	or more contributor license agreements.  See the NOTICE file
	distributed with this work for additional information
	regarding copyright ownership.  The ASF licenses this file
	to you under the Apache License, Version 2.0 (the
	"License"); you may not use this file except in compliance
	with the License.  You may obtain a copy of the License at
	
	http://www.apache.org/licenses/LICENSE-2.0
	
	Unless required by applicable law or agreed to in writing,
	software distributed under the License is distributed on an
	"AS IS" BASIS, WITHOUT WARRANTIES OR CONDITIONS OF ANY
	KIND, either express or implied.  See the License for the
	specific language governing permissions and limitations
	under the License.
-->
<section id="inspecting_configuration">
	<title>Inspecting the current configuration</title>
	<para>
		The
		<emphasis role="strong">
			Help >
			<imageobject>
				<imagedata scale="50" fileref="images/about.png"
					format="PNG" />
			</imageobject>
			About Apache Directory Studio
		</emphasis>
		dialog shows most of the important information about the
		features and plug-in configured in the product. To find out
		further detailed information about the current configuration:
	</para>
	<para>
		1. Open the update configuration manager by clicking
		<emphasis role="strong">
			Help > Software Updates >
			<imageobject>
				<imagedata scale="50"
					fileref="images/manage-configuration.png" format="PNG" />
			</imageobject>
			Manage Configuration
		</emphasis>
		. This opens the Product Configuration dialog.
	</para>
	<para>
		2. In the Product Configuration dialog expand the root node
		(current configuration). The first tier of items are locations
		on the local computer where the files for features and plug-ins
		are stored. For a typical product, all features are installed in
		a single directory sub-tree. However, a feature that is
		installed as an extension of another product are usually located
		in a separate directory sub-tree.
	</para>
	<para>
		3. Expand the location to see the feature versions installed
		there.
	</para>
	<para>
		4. The nesting of the features indicates which child features
		are included in a given parent feature. Nested features act as a
		unit.
	</para>
	<para>
		5. Select a feature version and click
		<emphasis role="strong">Show Properties</emphasis>
		to open the Properties dialog which presents more detailed
		information about the selected feature.
	</para>
	<para>
		6. Click
		<emphasis role="strong">Show Disabled Features</emphasis>
		filter on the toolbar of the Product Configuration dialog. Any
		feature versions that are disabled are now shown (you might not
		have any). Disabled feature versions are ones that are installed
		on the local computer but excluded from the current
		configuration. At most one version of any given feature can be
		present in a given configuration; usually the ones with the
		lower version numbers will be in a disabled state.
	</para>
	<para>
		7. In the Properties dialog of a feature, click
		<emphasis role="strong">Status</emphasis>
		to find out whether the selected feature is configured exactly
		as packaged. The status will show when a feature's plug-ins are
		present at different versions, or disabled due to missing
		prerequisite plug-ins that are expected to be supplied by some
		other feature.
	</para>
</section>