<!--
	Licensed to the Apache Software Foundation (ASF) under one
	or more contributor license agreements.  See the NOTICE file
	distributed with this work for additional information
	regarding copyright ownership.  The ASF licenses this file
	to you under the Apache License, Version 2.0 (the
	"License"); you may not use this file except in compliance
	with the License.  You may obtain a copy of the License at
	
	http://www.apache.org/licenses/LICENSE-2.0
	
	Unless required by applicable law or agreed to in writing,
	software distributed under the License is distributed on an
	"AS IS" BASIS, WITHOUT WARRANTIES OR CONDITIONS OF ANY
	KIND, either express or implied.  See the License for the
	specific language governing permissions and limitations
	under the License.
-->
<section id="updating">
	<title>Updating Apache Directory Studio</title>
	<para>
		To check to see whether there are updates for features of Apache
		Directory Studio (requires Internet access):
	</para>
	<para>
		1. Click
		<emphasis role="strong">
			Help > Software Updates >
			<imageobject>
				<imagedata contentdepth="1em"
					fileref="images/search-updates.png" format="PNG" />
			</imageobject>
			Search for updates...
		</emphasis>
		. This will contact Apache Directory Studio Web site to discover
		what versions of those features are available. The potential
		upgrades are presented in on the next page.
	</para>
	<para>
		2. Select the feature versions that you wish to upgrade, and
		click
		<emphasis role="strong">Next</emphasis>
		.
	</para>
	<para>
		3. Carefully review the license agreements for the upgraded
		features. If the terms of all these licenses are acceptable,
		check "I accept the terms in the license agreements." Do not
		proceed to download the features if the license terms are not
		acceptable.
	</para>
	<para>
		4. Feature versions can be digitally signed by the company that
		provides them. This allows you to verify more easily that the
		features and plug-ins that are about to be downloaded and
		installed are coming from a trusted supplier.
	</para>
	<para>
		Click
		<emphasis role="strong">Install</emphasis>
		to allow the downloading and installing to proceed.
	</para>
	<para>
		5. Once all the features and plug-ins have been downloaded
		successfully and their files installed into the product on the
		local computer, a new configuration that incorporates these
		features and plug-ins will be formulated. Click
		<emphasis role="strong">Yes</emphasis>
		when asked to exit and restart the Workbench for the changes to
		take effect.
	</para>

	&inspecting_configuration;
	&enabling_disabling_uninstalling_features;

</section>